## GustavoPenha guzpenha10@gmail.com

about	resear	rch	
27 years Delft, NL	I am a researcher in the field of computer science interested in the fields of IR, NLP, RecSys and ML. My focus is on ranking models for conversational search & recommendation. I like		
links webpage twitter github google scholar	to do research driven by curiosity, and one of my strengths is time management.		
	selected publications		
	2022	Evaluating the Robustness of Retrieval Pipelines with Query Variation Generators	
programming Python, C++, Spark, R		Gustavo Penha, Arthur Câmara, Claudia Hauff	
	2021	On the Calibration and Uncertainty of Neural Learning to Rank Models for Conversational Search  EACL  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff	
languages portuguese english	2020	Exploiting Performance Estimates for Augmenting Recommendation Ensembles  Gustavo Penha, Rodrygo Santos	
soft skills time management communication learn and adapt	2020	What does BERT know about books, movies and music? Probing BERT for Conversational Recommendation  RecSys  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff	
	2020	Curriculum Learning Strategies for IR: An Empirical Study on Conversation Response Ranking  ECIR  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff	

## **experience**

2021-5–8	<b>Applied Research Intern</b> <i>Voice search explanations for Alexa, resulted in 2 paper submissions.</i>	S
2015–2018	<b>Data Scientist</b> Machine learning and data science projects. Lead 1M R\$ ML project.	il
2014–2015	<b>Undergraduate Researcher</b> UFMG - Braze Research on scientific collaboration networks. Coauthor in 2 papers.	il

## education

2019-now	Ph.D.	TU Delft - Netherlands
	Computer Science	
2012–2018	B.Sc. and M.Sc. Computer Science	UFMG - Brazil